2030 Hudson St, Fort Lee, NJ 07024

9175471975

xuqingsally@gmail.com

Personal Website: https://xuqingsally.github.io/

Summary

With a Master's degree in biostatistics and experience of 1 year of data analysis and modeling in clinical data, I did projects of large interview population-based study, data manipulation, survival analysis, prediction model of psychosis and machine learning. I am familiar with SAS and R and very interested in clinical trials, longitudinal study, predictive models for health outcome and wish to contribute to research in healthcare.

Education

Master of Science: Biostatistics

Columbia University, Mailman School of Public Health

New York, NY, May, 2019

Courses: Probability, Biostatistics methods, Statistical Inference, Data Science, Epidemiology, Survival Analysis, Analysis of Longitudinal, Design of Medical Experiment, Randomized Clinical Trial

GPA: 3.77

Bachelor of Science: Biological Science

Nanjing University

Nanjing, China, Jun, 2017

GPA: 3.76

Working Experience

Biostatistics Data Analyst

Research Foundation for Mental Hygiene, New York, NY

Jul, 2019 - Present

- Conduct data analysis of longitudinal behavior data, including correlation matrix and logistic regression models
- Built risk calculator of conversion to psychosis based on lasso logistic regression with R
- Collaborate with clinicians for mental health paper publication

Biostatistics Research Assistant

Columbia University/New York State Psychiatric Institute, New York, NY

Jun, 2018 - May, 2019

- Conduct propensity score matching, survival analysis and logistics regression, including building cox survival models, plot survival functions and hazard curves with R, SAS SQL and SAS macro
- Machine Learning methods for schizophrenia prediction using random forest, boosting and regression models
- Help with data cleaning and make a codebook for a large survey database with SAS, SPSS and Excel
- Collaborate with biostatistician and medical researchers for clinical trial data analysis in heart failure and mental health

Research Biostatistician Intern

New York-Presbyterian Hospital, New York, NY

May, 2018 - Aug, 2018

- Explored clinical trial data of trauma among hospitals in New York by using surveys, generalized linear models, cross correlation analysis, longitudinal data analysis, ANOVA and mapping in R
- Collaborated and consulted with surgeons and biostatisticians by contributing to the statistical design, analysis of clinical trials, and other study designs to execute trauma clinical research
- Provided analytic support for clinical and regulatory reports and research papers
- Attended routine meetings for exploring and developing latest clinical designs

Submitted Paper

- Gary Brucato, Michael B. First, Qing Xu, Melanie M. Wall. (2019). Recency and Intensification of Positive Symptoms Enhance Prediction of Syndromal Psychosis in Clinical High-Risk Patients.
- Joseph A Gancayco, Weijia Fan, Qing Xu. (2019). Readmission after Mitral Valve Surgery for Functional Mitral Regurgitation: Detailed Insights into Heart Failure Recurrence and Healthcare Utilization.

Skills